EDISON ABDIEL

Software Developer & Operations Manager

professional skills

Excel

ZenDesk

BigQuery

Google Sheets

SheetGo

MySQL

JavaScript

Node.JS

React.JS

MongoDB

Express

Jest

Jasmine

enzime

personal skills

Challenge/result driven

Creative spirit

Reliable and professional

Organised

Time management

Team player

Fast learner

Empathetic

Motivated

Can-Do mentality

Active listening

Problem solving orientated

languages

Spanish

English

Italian

French

Portuguese

contact

+49 15222643589

the.edison.masis@gmail.com Reichenberger Str 153 10999 Berlin

references

Esteban Torres

Eng. Manager esteban.torres@soundcloud.com

Neil McDermott

Prg. Manager neil.mcdermott@soundcloud.com

Marc Tuduri

Senior Engineer
marc.tuduri@soundcloud.com

profile

Fullstack Engineer oriented mostly to Frontend development with relavant experience working experience in an Agile environment.

Open-minded and a quick learner, able to pick up on new processes, systems, and technologies quickly. Highly motivated team player who thrives while working collaboratively or independently. Excellent time management and multitasking skills. Known by peers for strong critical thinking, problem-solving abilities and high levels of motivation.

experience

Frontend Engineer

SoundCloud | 01/2020 to Present

Developed code to test components in development using Jest and enzyme Used frameworks for frontend development such as React and design software such as Photoshop and

Dreamweaver.

Assisted senior Front End Developers in designing web applications and gained skills in aligning designs with

client requirements.

Learned to interact with Product Managers, present designs and handle feedback on work-on-progress.

Deleted unused endpoints written in Ruby on Rails to improve backend performance.

Fixed multiple frontend issues for internal microservices and improved operational performance by adding tools

and features to the existing CMS

Content Operations Manager

SoundCloud | 09/2018 to 12/2019

The team didn't exist by the time I started. Together with 2 other colleagues, we developed the entire workflow, KPIs and basically the whole team from scratch. Today the team consists of 13 members and has added value to the overall performance of the platform.

Analysing the metadata of the catalogue content and assuring its adequate distribution.

Cleaning up the catalogue from possible copy rights infringements.

Operations Manager

Amazon | 02/2013 to 11/2015

Managed a team with a diverse array of talents and responsibilities. Ensured goals were met in areas including customer satisfaction, safety, QA and team member overall performance.

Implemented and managed changes and interventions to ensure project goals were always achieved.

Meeting with stakeholders and communicate in an easy and transparent manner topics regarding project goals and potential areas of improvement. Producing accurate and timely reporting of project status throughout its life cycle.

Analysed program risks and take action on solutions.

Working on strategy with the marketing team.

education

bachelor of Psychology

Universidad de Costa Rica | 20011 - 2015

Full stack development certificate

IronHack Berlin | 2019 - 2020